(コムギ)あの額当て 雨隠れの連中か。
Judging from their headbands,
they belong to the Hidden Rain...
(源内)巻物は天と地の
どっちを持ってるんだ？
Which scroll do they have?
Heaven or Earth?
(アジサイ)あっ。
逃げてばかりか。
All you do is run away!
(イナホ)おとなしく巻物を渡せ！
Just be nice and
hand over your scroll!
(スイレン)無駄ね。
(フヨウ)アジサイ。
That's not happening.
Ajisai...
火遁。
Fire Style!
開封術 紙吹雪。
Unsealing Jutsu! Confetti Storm!
(３人)うわぁ！
(源内)逃げたのか？
They ran away?
俺たちの実力に恐れをなしたな！
Our strength scared them off!
でも巻物を
手に入れそこなったわ。
Just when we almost had their scroll!
(２人)あぁ…。
Ready, set, go, we step over the goal line
isse nou se de fumikomu gourain
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
We look back as we pass the line, and it's already gone
issen koete furikaeruto mou nai
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
Fiercely, fiercely we move on
udatte udatte udatteku
Drenched in glistening sweat
kirameku ase ga koboreru no sa
There probably were a lot of things we didn't remember
oboetenai koto mo takusan atta darou
Everyone was just a silhouette
daremo kare mo shiruetto
Let's become adults,
daiji ni shitai mono motte otona ni naru nda
holding on to things we want to cherish
And let's keep on protecting them at all times
donna toki mo hanasazu ni mamori tsudzukeyou
Then someday...
soshitara itsu no hi ni ka
We'll be able to laugh at it all
nanimo kamo o waraerusa
Like the light and nimble dancing
hirari to hirari to matteru
Of leaves taking flight
konoha ga tonde yuku
Tenten's Troubles
((天使様。
天使様➡
Lady Angel...
Lady Angel,
what is our special mission?
私たちに特別任務とは
何でしょう？
(小南)中忍試験を利用して➡
Take advantage of the Chunin Exams
to find a Jinchuriki.
人柱力を捜し出してきなさい。
(アジサイ)人柱力ですか？
A Jinchuriki?
スイレン フヨウ。
あなたたちの感知能力で➡
Suiren, Fuyou...
Use your Sensory Perception skills
and look for a shinobi
膨大なチャクラを抱えた忍を
見つけなさい。
who harbors
an enormous amount of chakra.
それが人柱力なのですか？
Is that what a Jinchuriki is?
人柱力が見つからなくとも➡
Even if you don't find a Jinchuriki,
他里の優秀な忍がいたら
その情報を持ち帰ること。
bring back intel of any extraordinary
shinobi from other villages.
(２人)はい。
– Yes.
(小南)アジサイは
２人をフォローしなさい。
You will follow these two, Ajisai.
わかりました。
I understand.
雨隠れの里は今 改革の真っ最中。
The Hidden Rain is in
the midst of a reformation.
他里にはこれを
気取られないように。
Other villages must not find out.
雨隠れは 今なお
山椒魚の半蔵が➡
They must continue to believe
that Hanzo of the Salamander
治める里だと思わせておく。
rules the Hidden Rain.
(アジサイたち)はっ))
– Yes!
どうしたの？ アジサイ。
What is it, Ajisai?
よその国は
こんなにも星が見えるのね。
You can so see many stars
in other villages...
星か。
Stars, huh!
(スイレン)あれが星空。
So this is what a starlit sky is like...
あっ 流れ星。
初めて見たな。
Oh... a shooting star!
It's the first time I've seen one...
雨隠れにも
いつか必ず 星が降るわ。
We'll see them too, someday,
in Hidden Rain Village.
(リー)フー フー。
(テンテン)さてと。
Now then...
(ネジ)周囲に 他の忍はいない。
There's no other shinobi
in the area.
では 安心して食事がとれますね。
Okay, we can relax
and have a meal.
(テンテン)夕飯はお好み焼きよ。
We're having okonomiyaki
pancakes for dinner!
お好み焼き？
砂漠で➡
Okonomiyaki?
お好み焼きが食べれるとは。
Okonomiyaki in the desert...
Who would have expected that?
しっかり食べて しっかり
体力つけておかないとね。
We all need to eat well
and maintain our strength.
テンテンがいると便利ですね！
It's convenient
having you around, Tenten.
便利？
What do you mean
by "convenient"?
(リー)はい！ 便利で助かります。
It's so great that
you're so convenient!
便利って何よ。
便利な道具は出すけど➡
Excuse me?
I may have convenient tools,
私は便利な道具じゃ
ないんだからね。
but I am not
a convenient tool... okay?
いえいえ。
テンテンはしっかりと便利ですよ。
No, no!
You're absolutely convenient!
(テンテン)あ～ もう！
あっ。
Come on!
私は便利なんかじゃ
ないんだから！
I am not convenient!
ご飯の支度は任せるわよ！
You can prepare your own meal.
あの… テンテン。
Hey, Tenten...
ついてくるな！
Don't follow me!
どうしたんでしょう。
俺にもわからん。
I wonder what happened?
I don't know either.
どうしましょう！
俺に振るな。
What do we do?
Don't look at me.
あっ。
あ～あ。
八つ当たり… だよね。
That was just me venting, wasn't it?
((はぁ～！
八卦空掌！
8 Trigrams: Air Palm!
第三生門 開！
Third Gate of Life... Open!
ぬお～！
せいやっ！
あっ。
(ガイ)うむ。
腕を上げたな テンテン。
You've improved greatly, Tenten.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
免許皆伝の腕前だ。
You've perfected your skills.
でもね これじゃダメなのよ ガイ先生。
But it's not good enough,
Guy Sensei.
おっ どうした？
Oh? What's wrong?
武器を使った格闘戦なんて➡
Mastery with weapons
in one-on-one combat
忍者としたら基本のきでしょ？
is fundamental for a ninja, correct?
基本は大切だぞ。
Fundamentals are important.
わかってます でも➡
I know that.
問題は基本の先の応用です。
But the issue is going
beyond the fundamentals...
ネジは柔拳に磨きをかけ➡
Neji honed his Gentle Fist
and developed a new jutsu.
新術を開発したでしょ？
そのようだな すばらしい。
So I understand.
He's brilliant!
リーは基本のきの
体術しかないけど➡
Lee only has
fundamental taijutsu skills,
八門遁甲が開けるし。
but he can open
the Eight Inner Gates.
おう 修業のたまものだ。
It's the fruits of his labor!
でも 私には基本しかないでしょ？
But all I have is the basics.
ん？
私も何か応用が欲しいんです。
I want to apply my skills too.
このままじゃ 私➡
At this rate,
２人を後ろから
サポートするしかできないから。
all I'll ever do is stand behind them
and support them.
しかしな テンテン。
You know, Tenten,
such a role is crucial in teamwork.
チームには そういう
役割も必要なんだ。
そりゃあ ネジもリーも➡
I realize that both Neji and
Lee are taijutsu users
接近戦タイプの体術型でしょ？
who are close-contact fighters...
だから しかたないんだけど。
お前が後ろに控えて
サポートしてくれるから➡
We're able to fight aggressively
because we know that you have our back.
みんな安心して 前で戦える。
お前がいてくれることは
とてもありがたいんだ。
We're grateful that you're here for us.
ありがたいって言われるより
私も何か➡
Rather than gratitude,
I'd like to have
my own special ninjutsu.
特別な忍術が欲しいんです。
何かないですか？ ガイ先生。
Isn't there something, Guy Sensei?
う～む よし。
三節棍はどうだ？
How about the Sansetsukon?
それじゃ これと一緒です。
That's no different from this!
そうだ テンテン。
That's right, Tenten!
お前はこの班で
他の誰も真似できない➡
You have a trait no one else
on this team has.
能力があるではないか。
それを磨いたら どうだ？
You should polish that.
私だけの能力？
A skill no one else has?
うむ お前はとても便利なのだ。
You're really convenient
to have around.
便利だなんて 人を
道具扱いしないでください 先生。
Please don't talk about me
like I'm some tool, Sensei!
いや そういうつもりで
言ったんではないのだがな。
Oh no, I didn't mean it
like that at all.
もう 私だって➡
I'm asking you after giving this
a lot of thought, you know.
(いろいろ考えて
お願いしてるんですからね))
(リー)テンテン！
Tenten...
お好み焼きが焼けましたよ。
The okonomiyaki pancakes
are done.
食べましょう！
Let's eat!
味は大丈夫なの？
How do they taste?
あっ 自信はありませんが…。
I'm not too confident
about them, but...
今日も暑くなりそうだな。
Looks like it's going to
be another hot day.
雨隠れとは全然 違うわ。
It's the complete opposite
of Hidden Rain Village.
少し湿り気が欲しいわね。
A little dampness would be nice.
向こうに 緑が見える。
I see a little bit of green over there.
白眼！
Byakugan!
どうですか？ ネジ。
What do you see, Neji?
この辺りには 誰もいない。
There's no one around here.
じゃあ 先へ進もう。
Let's keep moving.
ゴールに近づけば
他のみんなだって➡
As we approach the finish line,
others are bound to appear.
集まってくるよ。
そうですね
待ち構えるのもありですから。
You're right.
It's better than lying in wait.
待ち構えるのなら➡
If we're going to wait,
I see a good spot.
都合のよさそうな場所がある。
どこです？
Where?
行ってみるか。
Want to go and check it out?
(テンテン)なんか妙な場所ね。
This place is eerie.
I see caves all around us.
(ネジ)あちこちに空洞が確認できる。
どうやら遺跡のようだ。
It seems to be a ruin.
A ruin?
(リー)遺跡？
ああ 風の国の…。
Yeah... of the Land of Wind.
フッ やはりか。
Just as I expected.
They're Hidden Leaf shinobi.
木ノ葉の忍ね。
They look different from
yesterday's bunch.
(フヨウ)昨日とは別のやつらだ。
Yesterday's trio was
totally unimpressive.
昨日の３人は まったく
たいしたことなかったけど。
今日のやつらは どうかな？
I wonder what these guys are like?
まっすぐこっちへ来るわよ。
They're heading right for us.
They have
a Sensory Perception type too.
(フヨウ)
向こうにも感知タイプがいるんだ。
迎え撃つまでよ。
We'll ambush them.
They're lying in wait.
待ち構えるようだな。
What about their scroll?
巻物はどうでしょうね。
We'll fight and snatch it away.
戦ってぶんどるまで！
Looks like they plan
to do the same thing.
どうやら向こうもそのつもりだ。
正面 来るぞ！
They're coming straight for us!
Let's not waste time
on senseless fighting.
無駄な戦闘に
時間を使いたくない。
単刀直入に言おう
俺たちの巻物は天だ。
I'll be blunt.
We have the Heaven scroll.
If this is what you're after, let's fight.
HEAVEN
お前たちが
これを欲しいというのなら➡
戦闘ということになる。
Unsealing Jutsu: Shuriken!
開封術 手裏剣！
That jutsu...!
あの術！
回転！
Rotation!
てや～！
口寄せ 雨水門！
Summoning Jutsu,
Gate of Rainwater!
お前…。
You...!
You're not the only one who
can use Transportation Ninjutsu.
時空間忍術を使うのは
あなただけじゃないのよ。
あいつら やるわね。
Those guys are pretty good.
Yeah, however...
ああ だが バカみたいなチャクラ量の
持ち主ではないな。
None of them are oozing with
large amounts of chakra.
アジサイ。
開封術 紙吹雪！
Ajisai...
Unsealing Jutsu! Confetti Storm!
FIRE
They ran away!
(リー)逃げた！
Byakugan!
白眼！
Let's go after them!
追うぞ。
追ってくる。
やはり 感知タイプがいるのね。
They're coming after us.
They definitely have
a Sensory type with them.
Water Style!
水遁 霧雨隠れの術。
Hidden Drizzle Jutsu!
What happened?
どうした？
こうも水気のない場所では
水遁の術は上手く使えないわ。
There's little moisture around here.
My Water style doesn't work well.
あっ！
地の利のないことは
百も承知よ。
I know we don't have
ground advantage.
It's an impossible battle,
but we have no choice but to fight.
無駄な戦闘だが やるしかない。
Leaf Hurricane!
木ノ葉旋風！
Above you, Lee!
上だ！ リー！
– Senbon Rainstorm!
(２人)如雨露千本！
は～っ！
やるわね。
You're pretty good!
Gentle Fist!
柔拳！ は～っ！
Leaf Drop!
木ノ葉落とし！
あっ！
ROPE
キャ～！
あ～っ！
テンテン！
Tenten!
アジサイ！
Ajisai!
奥底にチャクラを感じるが 深いな。
I sense their chakra underground...
but it's deep down.
The sand and gravel are in the way.
土砂が邪魔だ。
We can't waste time
fighting senselessly.
今は一刻を争う事態だ。
俺たちは 仲間を助け出す
邪魔はしないでほしい。
We're going to save our teammate,
so we request that you not interfere.
Same here.
私たちも同じだ。
そうです ここは一時
休戦といきましょう。
Yes, let's call a truce for now.
We're not at war.
戦争中じゃない
たかが試験の最中だ。
This is just the Chunin Exams.
合格 不合格よりも
仲間の安否が重要だ。
Our teammate's safety is more important
than passing or failing.
休戦は受け入れる。 だが
私たちは私たちで捜す。
We agree to your plan.
But we'll conduct our own search.
ここは 風の国の遺跡のようだ。
This looks like a ruin
of the Land of Wind.
Ajisai and the other shinobi fell
into an underground corridor.
アジサイたちが落ち込んだのは
その地下にある回廊では。
If it's a corridor,
it has to connect from somewhere.
地下回廊があるのなら
どこかでつながっているはずよ。
体力勝負で
上から掘っていきますか？
Should we just use brute strength
and dig from above?
There's a risk of collapse.
更なる落盤の恐れがある。
遺跡の通路を探して 地下を
たどったほうがいいだろう。
We should search for
a passageway into the ruin
and follow them underground.
Yikes...
((テンテン : うぅ…。
What's wrong?
そら どうした？
燃やせ 青春のファイア！
Burn with the passion of youth!
たぎらせろ 若き体力
たくわえろ 熱きチャクラ！
Let your youthful energy seethe!
Fill up with burning chakra!
But Guy Sensei...
でも ガイ先生！
I thought this is
just strength training!
これって 単に
体力強化じゃないんですか？
甘いな テンテン。 この崖の途中で➡
You're too easygoing, Tenten.
Somewhere along this cliff,
きっと
お前の体力は 限界を迎える。
your physical strength
will reach its limits.
だが それでは 叩き落ちて死ぬ。
Then you will fall and die.
死ぬ？
死なぬためには➡
Die?
To prevent yourself from dying,
you must overcome the limits
of your physical strength.
体力の限界をこえるしかない。
体力の限界をこえるために
必要なのは 強い精神力だ。
Overcoming the limits of
physical strength requires a strong will.
はい…。
Yes sir!
Hi there.
Are you guys cliff-climbing too?
(カカシ)よう お前らも
崖登りの修業か？
お疲れさん。
カカシ！
Hang in there.
Kakashi?!
お前 なんだ？ その格好は。
Why is your arm
behind your back?
あ？ なんか
習慣になっちゃってね。
It's a little habit of mine.
じゃ お先に。
Well, see you later!
何がお先にだ！ 待て！ 勝負だ！
"See you later"?
Wait up! This is a contest!
先は俺だ！
I'm finishing first!
(カカシ)そんな
ムキになることないでしょう。
Don't get so worked up.
This is only training.
修業なんだから。
What's wrong with
a little rivalry during training!
修業で競って何が悪い！
Hey, please wait, Guy Sensei!
ねぇ～ 待って ガイ先生！
You can take it easy!
(ガイ)お前は ゆっくりでいいぞ！
もう！
Jeez!
あ～！
クソ～ クソ～！ クソ～ッ！
Damn, damn it...
Damn it...
おお テンテン
よく登ってきたな。
Good job, Tenten. You made it.
どうだ？ 限界をこえたか？
Well? Did you overcome your limits?
よくわからないけど 何か
こえてきたような気はします。
I'm not quite sure...
But I think I overcame something.
水は？
Water?
どうぞ。
やはり 便利だなぁ。
Here you go.
You're convenient, after all.
便利は やめてください。
Please stop saying that already.
便利なのは お前の術だ。
I mean, your jutsu is convenient.
巻物に 物を収納したり➡
Storing items in a scroll,
巻物で 物を
遠くから引き寄せたりするのは➡
or using a scroll to pull things
from a distance...
口寄せの術に属する
時空間忍術の一種だ。
The Transportation Technique,
which is a type of Summoning Jutsu.
素質の ありなしが ものをいう。
You either have the skill
for it or you don't.
You're saying that
I have the skill for it?
私には その素質が
あるということですか？
そのようだ。
それに磨きをかけるのが➡
Seems that way.
Honing that skill is the path
to gaining the strength
and usefulness you desire.
お前の言う応用
強くなる道筋だろう。
磨きをかけるって
身体強化ばかりじゃないですか。
Hone my skill?
Isn't that only going to increase
my physical strength?
精神強化もだ。
Your spiritual strength too.
チャクラは
身体エネルギーと精神エネルギーを➡
You know that chakra
is the combination
of physical energy and
spiritual energy, right?
練り合わせたものだ
とは知っているな？
Of course.
当然。
(ガイ)個人の持つ➡
Each individual can increase
chakra simply by training.
チャクラの量というものは
少なからず➡
修業によって
増やすことができる。
Simply put, if you increase
your physical and spiritual power,
つまり 体力と精神力を増やせば➡
your chakra will increase too.
おのずと チャクラ量も増えるのだ。
チャクラ量を増やすと
私に メリットがあるんですか？
Increasing my chakra
is good for me?
口寄せの術とは
術者のチャクラ量に比例して➡
With Summoning Jutsu,
the caster's chakra
is directly proportionate
呼び寄せるものの
量や大きさが増えるのだ。
to the quantity and size
of what is summoned.
お前は 今 これだけの量の水を
口寄せしたが➡
This is the amount of water
you just summoned.
チャクラ量が増えれば
風呂桶くらい 湖くらい➡
By increasing your chakra,
you can summon enough water
to fill a bathtub,
or a lake, or even an ocean.
大海くらいと
量が増えていくのだ。
大海…。
An ocean...
OCEAN
おっと！
うわぁ～！
フフフフ！
そういうわけで➡
And that is why we will continue
to train to increase our chakra, Tenten.
チャクラ量を増やす修業を続けるぞ。
テンテン。
はい！
Right!
登ったのに なんで
逆におりるんですか！
We just climbed up,
so why are we climbing down?!
This is training too!
これも修業だ！
燃やせ 青春のファイア！
Burn with the passion of youth!
Let your youthful energy seethe!
たぎらせろ 若き体力！
たくわえろ チャクラ！
Fill up with burning chakra!
熱き…。
はぁ？
Huh?
(キャーッ!!))
ここは？
Where am I?
あっ。
Hey, are you all right?
ねぇ ちょっと大丈夫？
ねえってば！
Hey... come on!
nando tatakitsukerarete mo
No matter how many times I get beat down
akiramerareru wake nado wanaku genten kaiki
I can't give up, so I go back to my basics
genjitsu to wa baibai shite
I wish we could say bye-bye to this reality
mukashi mitai ni waiwai shitai keredo
And have fun like we used to
sou mo ikanai nara kirihiraite mirya ii
But it doesn't work that way,
so let's carve out our own paths
nokori wazuka no shouki torimodoshite
I'll make you get back the little sanity you have left
me no mae no tobira kojiakete miseru
And then tear down the door in front of you
itsudemo sou nanda
That's the way it is
wasuregachina koto ga
The things you tend to forget
nani yori mo taisetsuna koto datte
Are the things that are the most important
nani ga machiukete iyou to kamawanai
I don't care what lies ahead
ame nimo makezu yami o terasu
The rain won't stop me from lighting up the darkness
kono kyoujin na kokoro ga areba
As long as I have this strong spirit
kono toki kono basho ni tsudoishi nakamatachi
Friends who gather at this time, at this place
mawari tsudzukeru sekai nanbitotari
The world keeps spinning, No one can stop it
tomo tomeru koto wa dekinai yo
Lee, did you find something?
<旬の小鉢が大好きな豆助>
No, I thought it was an entrance into
the ruins, but it was just a boulder.
♪～
I see...
We have to find
the entrance quickly.
We don't know how long we have
until everything caves in,
≫豆助
due to that previous shockwave...
きょうは今が旬の
アレを使った小鉢よ？
Oh no!
Can't you find them with
your Byakugan, Neji?
Well, it seems they fell down
a considerable distance...
< その小鉢とは？>
Tenten...
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Imprisoned Pair"
I hope you are safe!